Ronarro L. Cleveland, II

Junior Software Engineer

Houston, TX 77068 | (313)333-8578 | rcleveland30@gmail.com | LinkedIn | GitHub

Summary

Junior software engineer completing Full-Stack certification with DigitalCrafts with a desire to learn, grow, and evolve within the profession. Practiced in HTML, CSS, JavaScript, & APIs to develop front-end projects. Licensed teacher with 7+ years of experience in skills such as creativity, critical thinking, patience, and time management.

Skills

Leadership: Strategic Planning & Execution, Project Management, Prioritization, Process Improvement, Collaboration **Software**: HTML, JavaScript, CSS, React.js, RESTful APIs, PostgreSQL, Express.js, Node.js, PowerShell

Education & Certification

DigitalCrafts | Certificate in Software Engineering | Atlanta, GA

May 2022 - Nov 2022

Alabama State University | B.A., History

Aug 2008 - May 2012

Projects | Portfolio

American University Football Saturday | Demo | github.com/rcleveland30/cfbproject

November 2022

- Application allows users to search for college football games and store the game to a database
- Users can search through games played from the previous week, in the current week, and games to be played in the following week.
- Final capstone built with CSS, JavaScript, React.js, Redux

GameTyme | Live Demo | github.com/oAndRFullStack

Sept 2022

- Member of 2-person development team building an application that allows users to search for videos games and leave a review for the games they selected
- Primary responsibilities included calling the API, styling the review pages, as well as logging reviews to database
- Built with HTML, CSS, JavaScript, BootStrap, PostgreSQL, Express.js, Node.js

Nourriture | Demo | github.com/foodProject2022

Aug 2022

- Member of 4-person development team designing an application that allows users to search for recipes by various filters
- Primary responsibilities include design of 'About' view as well as general styling of application
- Built with HTML, CSS, JavaScript, BootStrap

Employment History

Teacher | Aldine ISD Aug 2015-Present

- Responsible for managing and teaching approximately 300 high school students per year in Psychology & Sociology
- Achieved 88% student pass rate per year by creating classroom atmosphere to maintain student interest and facilitate learning
- Work collaboratively and communicate effectively with students, administrators, teachers, and parents to ensure student success.

Substitute Teacher | Houston ISD, Spring ISD

Dec 2014- May 2015

- Administered lessons designed by teachers for approximately 75 classes
- Monitored and managed the behavior of approximately 25 students per class.
- Received 100% positive feedback from classroom teachers.

Extracurricular Leadership

Official (Football, Basketball, Baseball) | Texas Association of Sports Officials

Aug 2017- Present

Volunteer Coach | Aldine Davis High School Baseball

Jan 2016 - May 2018